Dimitris Mavrokapnidis

Address:

22 Calvert Avenue, E27JP, London, UK E-mail:

dimitris.mavrokapnidis@gmail.com Mobile:

(+44) 7586545238

Website:

dimavrok.github.io/home

Profile

5+ years of research and experience working complex systems thinking, information modeling, data science, and the Internet of Things in the context of the built environment.

Driven by the creation of practical software and data architectures that provide scalable solutions to complex problems and novel ideas.

Technical Skills

RDF/SPARQL	•••••
Neo4j	
Python	
JavaScript	
HTML	
ETL	
UML	
XML/JSON	
IFC/gbXML	00000
Revit/Dynamo	
EnergyPlus	
Modelica	

Languages

English	•••••
Greek	00000
French	••000

Awards



1st prize in Hackathon of LDAC 2022 Summer School at Cercedilla Spain https://linkedbuildingdata.ne t/ldac2022/summerschool/

Interests

- Football
- Snowboarding
- Travelling

Professional Experience



Sep. 2020 - present London, UK

Research Fellow

University College London

Research Fellow in Semantic Technologies for Digital Twins

- Leading and managing the implementation of a scalable Data Lake and Building Analytics Platform architecture for EU's Horizon 2020 project "DigiBuild"
 - o Providing technical guidance to the development of UCL's Marshgate Digital Twin pilot.
- Researching the intersection of Knowledge Graphs and LLMs for querying building data, using Langchain, ChromaDB, and OpenAl's API.

Marie-Curie Research Fellow in Cloud-BIM

- Extensive training in OpenBIM, Cloud and Semantic Technologies.
- Developed ETL tools, data quality checking mechanism and a logical inferencing engine to automate building data integrations using ifcopenshell, RDFlib and pySHACL python libraries.
- Created SeeQ: a Python library to facilitate development of portable applications
 - o Presented work and collaborated with Siemens' AG R&D department at Zug, Switzerland.
- Presented research outputs in 5 different conferences.



Sep. 2022 - Jan. 2023 Golden, Colorado, USA

Computer Science Intern

Colorado School of Mines

- Collaborated with Dr. Gabe Fierro to devise a novel programming abstraction for portable smart building applications.
- Create and test a set of portable smart building applications based on Brick Schema.



Jan. 2020 - Jul. 2021 Atlanta, Georgia, USA

Research Assistant

Network Dynamics Lab (NDL), Georgia Tech

Implemented time-series forecasting models and computer vision algorithms for the development of a Smart City Digital Twin prototype for the City of Columbus, Georgia.



Nov. 2017 - Aug. 2018 Athens, Greece

Software Developer

ACE-Hellas

Collaborated with software engineers and supported the development of the Optimisation Computing Platform (OCP) to include Energy and CO2 emissions parameters.

Education



PhD, Enabling Smart Building Operation at Scale University College London (UCL)

2020 - present London, UK

Minor: Knowledge Representation and Graph Databases

- Research Topic: Investigating scalable information modelling practices to facilitate data discovery and application development for large building portfolios.



London, UK

MSc, Smart Buildings and Digital Engineering University College London (UCL),

- 1-year program ("Distinction") with focus on Building Physics, Building Automation, Energy Management Systems, HVAC Control, Machine Learning
- Thesis: "Model Predictive Control for Buildings-to-Grid integration using dynamic electricity pricing"



2012 - 2017

Athens, Greece

MEng, Civil and Environmental Engineering

National Technical University of Athens (NTUA)

- 5-year program: Applied Maths and Physics with focus on Computational Structural Optimisation and Sustainability
- Thesis (Excellent Grade 10/10): "Environmental assessment of cost-optimised structural systems in tall buildings" - Published in Journal of Building Engineering